<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The prices of fares and passages to be paide unto watermen from London to Grauesende, and likewise from Grauesend to London, and to euery common place betwene and also betwene London Bridge and Windesoure, and so to euery common place of landyng betwene London Bridge and Windesoure.</title>
            <author>Watermen's Company (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1555</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06319</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16787.2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S3005</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">29649883</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 29649883</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28065</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06319)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28065)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1861:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The prices of fares and passages to be paide unto watermen from London to Grauesende, and likewise from Grauesend to London, and to euery common place betwene and also betwene London Bridge and Windesoure, and so to euery common place of landyng betwene London Bridge and Windesoure.</title>
                  <author>Watermen's Company (London, England)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 leaves.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Jmprinted at London in Powles Churcheyarde, by John Cawood, prynter to the Quenes Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[ca. 1555]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>"Cum priuilegio Regiæ Maiestatis."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Society of Antiquaries.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Watermen's Company (London, England)</term>
               <term>Shipping --  England --  London.</term>
               <term>Water transfer --  England --  London.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  16th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="list_of_ferry_fares">
                  <pb facs="tcp:28065:1"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 41 -->
                  <head>
                     <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> The prices of Fares and <hi>paſſages to be paide vnto watermen from London to Graueſende, and</hi> like wiſe from Graueſende to London, and to euery com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon place betwene. And alſo betwene London Bridge and Windeſoure, and ſo to euery common place of landyng betwene London Bridge and Wyndeſoure.</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N Primis that no owner or occupier of the common fare of Graueſende barge, ſhall take of any perſon from London to Graueſende, or contrarye a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue two pence for euery perſon, ſo as the ſame ſume of two pence for euery perſon amount to the ſume of <hi>iiij. s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or occupier of any tylte boate with iiii. ores and a ſtereſman, take for his fare from London to Graueſende, to or fro aboue foure pence the perſon, ſo as the ſame foure pence a man do amount to vi. s viii. d. &amp; for euery ore aboue foure ores to haue xii. d. an ore <hi>.vj. s. viij. d</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that euerye owner or occupier of a whirrey from London to Graueſende to or fro, ſhal not take anye more for hys whole fare, yf he be requyred, then ij. s.</item>
                     <item>Item, that the owner or occupyer of a tyde boate from London to Grenehyue or grayes Thorrock, or to any place of lyke dyſtaunce, ſhall not take of anye one perſonne to or fro aboue a penye, ſo as the whole fare mounte to <hi>xij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, for a tilte boate with foure ores and a ſlereſman to and fro not aboue .vi. s. and for euery ore aboue foure ores xii. d. an ore <hi>.vj. s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrrey with two ores take from London to Grene hyue, Greyes Thorock, or like diſtaunce to or fro aboue <hi>xx. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item,that no owner or occupyer of any tide boate from London to Purflete or lyke diſtaunce, to or fro, ſhal take of any one perſonne aboue a penye, ſo as the hole fare maye amounte vnto, <hi>x. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, for a tilte boate with foure ores and a ſtereſman from Lon<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>don to Grith or Purflete, or like diſtaunce, to or fro, not aboue fyue ſhyllynges for hys whole fare <hi>.v. s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman with two ores take from London to Purflet or lyke dyſtaunce to or fro, aboue <hi>xviij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:28065:2"/>
                        <!-- PDF PAGE 42 -->Item, that no owner or occupyer of anye tyde boate frome Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don to Rayneham or Erith, or like diſtaunce to or fro doo take aboue a peny of any one perſon.</item>
                     <item>Item, for a tylte boate with foure ores and a ſtereſman to or fro not aboue fyue ſhyllynges for his whole fare <hi>.v. s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrrymanne wyth two ores take from London to Rayneham, or Erith, or lyke diſtaunce aboue <hi>.xvj. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or occupyer of anye tyde boate frome Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don to Wolwich, or lyke diſtaunce, to or fro, take of any perſon aboue a peny.</item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman with two ores take for his fare frome London to Wolwich to or fro, aboue <hi>.xij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that none of the occupiers of anye of the common tyde botes afore reherſed, ſhall take of anye perſon, that ſhall come aborde of any of the ſayde boats by the waye betwene London and Graueſ<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ende aboue the pryce for the ſame boate limitted.</item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a payre of ores, ſhal take for his whole fare from London to Grenewich to or for aboue <hi>.viij. d.</hi> with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide .xiid</item>
                     <item>Item, no whyrrymanne wyth a payre of ores, ſhall take for his fare from Ratcliffe to Grenewich, or contrarye aboue. <hi>iiij. d.</hi> with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide .vi d</item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a payre of ores, take for his fare fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Lodon to Ratcliffe or Limehouſe or like diſtaunce to or fro aboue <hi>iiij. d.</hi> with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide .vi d</item>
                     <item>Item, that from Lyon keye, or Saynt Oliffes, to. S. Katherine or Radriffe, or like diſtaunce, no whyrryman take for his fare aboue <hi>ij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a pare of ores, take for his fare from the olde Swanne, P<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>per Alley, Saynt Mary Oueries or the three cranes, to Weſtminſter, Lambeth, Whitehall, or lyke diſtaunce to or fro aboue <hi>.iiij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo whyrrymanne wyth a payre of ores, take for his fare, from Pawles wharfe, Quene hithe, Pariſhe garden or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> blacke Fryers to Weſtminſter, or White hal, or lyke diſtau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce to or fro aboue <hi>iij. d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrryman wyth two ores, take from the Whyte Fryers, or te<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ple brydge, to white Hal, or Weſtminſter, to or for aboue <hi>ij d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, the lyke pryce from White Friers, or Temple bridge, to Saynt Marye Oueryes, Pepper Alley or thre cranes to or fro.</item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrrye take for his fare from the olde Swanne, Pepper Alley, Sayncte Marye Oueryes ſtayres, the three Cranes, or Quene hirh, to or fro Lambeth aboue.<note place="margin">iiij. d.</note>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:28065:3"/>
                        <!-- PDF PAGE 43 -->Item, that no whyrrey take fro Pawles Warfe, Pariſhe Garden the Blacke Fryers, or Whyte Fryers, to Lambeth to or fro aboue <hi>.iij.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyrrey with a pare of ores, doo take for hys fare, croſſe ouer the water betwene London bridge &amp; Weſtm. not aboue<hi>.j.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo ſkuller take croſſe ouer the water, with a pare of ſculles for hys fare aboue. <hi>o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>
                        </hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo whyrryman with a pare of ores take for hys fare from london to Chelſey, or like diſtaunce to or fro aboue <hi>.vj.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo whyrrey man with a pare of ores take of anye per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon from London to Putney, Fullam, or Barnelmes to or fro for his whole fare aboue <hi>.x.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or his deputie of anye tilte boate with foure ores, and a ſtereſman take for his fare from london to Chelſey or like diſtaunce to and fro, ſo that the boate do go and come in a day, or els to agre with the owner or occupyer thereof not aboue fyue ſhillings and for euery ore aboue foure ores, twelue pence an ore <hi>.v.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tylte boate, with foure ores and a ſtereſman, take for his fare from london to Putney or lyke diſtaunce, ſo that the boate do go and come in one day, not aboue vi.s and for euery ore aboue foure ores to haue twelue pence an ore <hi>.vj.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo whyrrey with a payre of ores, take of anye perſon, from london vnto Cheſwicke or Mortlake, or lyke dyſtaunce for hys whole fare to or fro aboue <hi>.xvj.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tilte boate with foure ores and a ſtereſman, take for hys fare from London to Cheſwicke or Mortlake or like diſtaunce to or fro (ſo that the boate do go &amp; come in one day) not aboue vi.s. &amp; for euery ore aboue iiii. ores .xii.d. an ore <hi>.vj.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, no whyrryman with a pare of ores to take of any perſonne from london vnto Brayneford, Thiſtelworth, Richmond bancke, or Twyckenham for hys fare to or fro aboue.<hi>.xviij.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that noo owner of a tylte boate or his deputye, wyth foure ores and a ſtereſman, do take for his fare from london to Breineford Thiſtelworth, Rychmonde Bancke, Twighnam, Tuddington, and Kingſton, or like diſtaunce, to and fro (ſo that the boate may goo and come in one day) nor aboue .vi.s.vii.d. and for euery ore aboue foure ores to haue twelue pence an ore <hi>.vj.<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap> viij d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <pb facs="tcp:28065:4"/>
                        <!-- PDF PAGE 44 -->Item, the common tilte boate of Kinſton not to take of anye one perſon from thenſe to london or contrary aboue foure pence a peace.</item>
                     <item>Item, no whyryman with a payre of ores to take for hys whole fare from london to Toddington or kingſton to or fro aboue <hi>.xx.d.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, no whyryman with a pare of ores to take for his whole fare from London to Hampton Courte, to or fro aboue <hi>.ij.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, no owner or occupyer of anye tylte boate ſhall take for hys fare from london to Hampton towne, with iiii. ores,  and a ſtereſman aboue viii.s. and for euery ore aboue iiii. ores xii.d. an ore <hi>.viij.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, no whyrriman to take for his whole fare from London to Otelandes, or or fro aboue <hi>.iij.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tylte boate, with foure ores &amp; a ſtereſman take for his fare from london to Sonbery, Wilto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, Sheperton, Maybrydge, Otelandes, Cherſey, or Stanes, to or fro, not aboue nine ſhyllynges, and for euerye ore aboue iiii. ores twelue pence an ore <hi>.ix.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no whyryman take for his fare from london to wynd<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoure aboue <hi>.iiij.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Item, that no owner or hys deputie, of any tylte boate wyth foure ores, and a ſtereſman, take for his fare from London to Wyndeſoure, not aboue .x.s. and for euery ore aboue .iiii. ores .xii.d. an ore <hi>.x.s.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
                  <closer>God ſaue the Quene.
<signed>
                        <list>
                           <item>Bacon. C.S.</item>
                           <item>Penbroke.</item>
                           <item>E. Rogers.</item>
                           <item>VV. Peter.</item>
                           <item>VV. Northamton.</item>
                           <item>E. Clynton.</item>
                           <item>F. Knolles.</item>
                           <item>Ri. Sackefyld.</item>
                           <item>F. Bedforde.</item>
                           <item>VV. Havvarde.</item>
                           <item>VV. Ciſſell.</item>
                           <item>N. VVotton.</item>
                        </list>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </body>
            <back>
               <div type="colophon">
                  <p>
                     <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London in Powles Churcheyarde, by Iohn Cawood, Prynter to the Quenes Maieſtie.</p>
               </div>
               <div xml:lang="lat" type="license">
                  <p>Cum priuilegio Regiae Maieſtatis.</p>
               </div>
            </back>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <body>
               <div type="list_of_ferry_fares">
                  <pb facs="tcp:28065:5"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 45 -->
                  <head>The Rates and Pryces that euery pertyculer perſon ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth to paye for his fare or paſſage vnto Watermen or Whir<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>reymen from London Brydge to Wyndeſoure, and likewyſe from Wyndeſoure to London Brydge, and to euerye common landyng place betwene the ſame two places hereafter is breifely declared.</head>
                  <p>
                     <table>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> thold ſwa<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Peper ally ſ. ma<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ry oueries, or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> three Cranes.</cell>
                           <cell>THe hole fare of a whyrrey with .ii. ores. to Weſtminſter, Lam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth, Whitehall, or other places of like diſtaunce to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell>iiii.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> poules wha<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rfe quenehith pa<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>riſh garden or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Blacke Friers.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with two ores to Weſtmynſter, or Whytehall, or other place of lyke dyſtaunce.</cell>
                           <cell>iii. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> whyte fryers or Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple Brygde.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a Whyrrey with two ores to Whythall or Weſt<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>minſter to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell>ii.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell> From y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> whyte fryers or Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple Brygde.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with two ores to Saint Mary Oue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reys, Pepper Alley, or the iii. cranes to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell>.ii.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> paules whar<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fe, pariſh garde<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the blacke friers or whitefryers.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with two ores to or fro Lambeth.</cell>
                           <cell>iii.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="2"> Croſſynge the Ryuer.</cell>
                           <cell>A whyrrey with two ores for croſſynge ouer the Ryuer betwene London Brydge and Weſtmynſter.</cell>
                           <cell>i.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>A Sculler for the lyke labour.</cell>
                           <cell>ob.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From London Brydge to chel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſey to and fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>vi.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From London to putney, Ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham or barnel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mes to and fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>x.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to chelſey or a like diſtau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce to &amp; fro</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a Tylte boate with .iiii. ores and a Stereſman for one daye.</cell>
                           <cell>v.s</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to Putney or lyke diſtau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce to &amp; fro</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a tylte bote with foure ores and a ſtereſman for one daye.</cell>
                           <cell>vi.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="2">From cheſwike or Mortlake or lyke dyſtaunce to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>xvi.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Of a tylte boate with iiii. ores and a ſtereſman for one day.</cell>
                           <cell>vi.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="2">From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to brayneford thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtelworth rych<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mond banke, or twyckenham, to and fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>xviii.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>And of a tylte boate with .iiii. ores and a ſtereſman to or fro the ſayde places &amp; alſo to or fro Todingto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> &amp; Kingſton for one day.</cell>
                           <cell>vi.s.viii.d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to kingſton or tud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dington to &amp; fro</cell>
                           <cell>The fare of one perſonne in the common tylte boate of the ſayde towne.</cell>
                           <cell> iiii.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to hamton Courte to and fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell> xx.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to otela<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds to &amp; fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>ii.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="2">From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to Sonbery Wilto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ſheaperto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, Way bridge, Otela<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds chartſeye or ſta<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nes to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell>And of a tylte boate with iiii. ores and a ſtereſman.</cell>
                           <cell> viii.s</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>iii.s</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="3">From londo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to Windeſoure to and fro.</cell>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a tylte boate with iiii. ores and a ſtereſman.</cell>
                           <cell>ix.s</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>The hole fare of a whyrrey to or fro with ores.</cell>
                           <cell>iiii.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>And of a tylte boate with iiii. ores and a ſtereſman.</cell>
                           <cell>x.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell rows="34">
                              <pb facs="tcp:28065:6"/>
                              <!-- PDF PAGE 46 -->
 </cell>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or occupyer of anye tyde boate frome Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don to Rayneham or Erith, or like diſtaunce to or fro doo take aboue a peny of any one perſon.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, for a tylte boate with foure ores and a ſtereſman to or fro not aboue fyue ſhyllynges for his whole fare.</cell>
                           <cell>v. s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrrymanne wyth two ores take from London to Rayneham, or Erith, or lyke diſtaunce aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>xvj. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or occupyer of anye tyde boate frome Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don to Wolwich, or lyke diſtaunce, to or fro, take of any perſon aboue a peny.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrryman with two ores take for his fare frome London to Wolwich to or fro, aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>xij. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that none of the occupiers of anye of the common tyde botes afore reherſed, ſhall take of anye perſon, that ſhall come aborde of any of the ſayde boats by the waye betwene London and Graueſ<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ende aboue the pryce for the ſame boate limitted.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a payre of ores, ſhal take for his whole fare from London to Grenewich to or for aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>viij. d. with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide .xiid</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no whyrrymanne wyth a payre of ores, ſhall take for his fare from Ratcliffe to Grenewich, or contrarye aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iiij. d. with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> vi d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a payre of ores, take for his fare fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> Lodon to Ratcliffe or Limehouſe or like diſtaunce to or fro aboue</cell>
                           <cell>iiij. d. with the tyde, &amp; againſt tide<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> vi d</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that from Lyon keye, or Saynt Oliffes, to. S. Katherine or Radriffe, or like diſtaunce, no whyrryman take for his fare aboue</cell>
                           <cell>ij. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrryman wyth a pare of ores, take for his fare from the olde Swanne, Peper Alley, Saynt Mary Oueries or the three cranes, to Weſtminſter, Lambeth, Whitehall, or lyke diſtaunce to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iiij. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo whyrrymanne wyth a payre of ores, take for his fare, from Pawles wharfe, Quene hithe, Pariſhe garden or y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> blacke Fryers to Weſtminſter, or White hal, or lyke diſtau<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ce to or fro aboue</cell>
                           <cell>iij. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrryman wyth two ores, take from the Whyte Fryers, or te<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ple brydge, to white Hal, or Weſtminſter, to or for aboue</cell>
                           <cell>ij d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, the lyke pryce from White Friers, or Temple bridge, to Saynt Marye Oueryes, Pepper Alley or thre cranes to or fro.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrrye take for his fare from the olde Swanne, Pepper Alley, Sayncte Marye Oueryes ſtayres, the three Cranes, or Quene hirh, to or fro Lambeth aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iiij. d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <pb facs="tcp:28065:7"/>
                              <!-- PDF PAGE 47 -->
Item, that no whyrrey take fro Pawles Warfe, Pariſhe Garden the Blacke Fryers, or Whyte Fryers, to Lambeth to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iij.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyrrey with a pare of ores, doo take for hys fare, croſſe ouer the water betwene London bridge &amp; Weſtm. not aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>j.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo ſkuller take croſſe ouer the water, with a pare of ſculles for hys fare aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap>
                           </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo whyrryman with a pare of ores take for hys fare from london to Chelſey, or like diſtaunce to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>vj.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo whyrrey man with a pare of ores take of anye per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon from London to Putney, Fullam, or Barnelmes to or fro for his whole fare aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>x.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or his deputie of anye tilte boate with foure ores, and a ſtereſman take for his fare from london to Chelſey or like diſtaunce to and fro, ſo that the boate do go and come in a day, or els to agre with the owner or occupyer thereof not aboue fyue ſhillings and for euery ore aboue foure ores, twelue pence an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>v.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tylte boate, with foure ores and a ſtereſman, take for his fare from london to Putney or lyke diſtaunce, ſo that the boate do go and come in one day, not aboue vi.s and for euery ore aboue foure ores to haue twelue pence an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>vj.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo whyrrey with a payre of ores, take of anye perſon, from london vnto Cheſwicke or Mortlake, or lyke dyſtaunce for hys whole fare to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>xvj.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tilte boate with foure ores and a ſtereſman, take for hys fare from London to Cheſwicke or Mortlake or like diſtaunce to or fro (ſo that the boate do go &amp; come in one day) not aboue vi.s. &amp; for euery ore aboue iiii. ores .xii.d. an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>vj.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no whyrryman with a pare of ores to take of any perſonne from london vnto Brayneford, Thiſtelworth, Richmond bancke, or Twyckenham for hys fare to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>xviij.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that noo owner of a tylte boate or his deputye, wyth foure ores and a ſtereſman, do take for his fare from london to Breineford Thiſtelworth, Rychmonde Bancke, Twighnam, Tuddington, and Kingſton, or like diſtaunce, to and fro (ſo that the boate may goo and come in one day) nor aboue .vi.s.vii.d. and for euery ore aboue foure ores to haue twelue pence an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>vj.<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                                 <desc>•</desc>
                              </gap> viij d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>
                              <pb facs="tcp:28065:8"/>
                              <!-- PDF PAGE 48 -->
Item, the common tilte boate of Kinſton not to take of anye one perſon from thenſe to london or contrary aboue foure pence a peace.</cell>
                           <cell> </cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no whyryman with a payre of ores to take for hys whole fare from london to Toddington or kingſton to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>xx.d.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no whyryman with a pare of ores to take for his whole fare from London to Hampton Courte, to or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>ij.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no owner or occupyer of anye tylte boate ſhall take for hys fare from london to Hampton towne, with iiii. ores,  and a ſtereſman aboue viii.s. and for euery ore aboue iiii. ores xii.d. an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>viij.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, no whyrriman to take for his whole fare from London to Otelandes, or or fro aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iij.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or his deputie of any tylte boate, with foure ores &amp; a ſtereſman take for his fare from london to Sonbery, Wilto<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, Sheperton, Maybrydge, Otelandes, Cherſey, or Stanes, to or fro, not aboue nine ſhyllynges, and for euerye ore aboue iiii. ores twelue pence an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>ix.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no whyryman take for his fare from london to wynd<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoure aboue.</cell>
                           <cell>iiij.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                           <cell>Item, that no owner or hys deputie, of any tylte boate wyth foure ores, and a ſtereſman, take for his fare from London to Wyndeſoure, not aboue .x.s. and for euery ore aboue .iiii. ores .xii.d. an ore.</cell>
                           <cell>x.s.</cell>
                        </row>
                     </table>
                  </p>
                  <closer>God ſaue the Quene.
<signed>
                        <list>
                           <item>Bacon. C.S.</item>
                           <item>Penbroke.</item>
                           <item>E. Rogers.</item>
                           <item>VV. Peter.</item>
                           <item>VV. Northamton.</item>
                           <item>E. Clynton.</item>
                           <item>F. Knolles.</item>
                           <item>Ri. Sackefyld.</item>
                           <item>F. Bedforde.</item>
                           <item>VV. Havvarde.</item>
                           <item>VV. Ciſſell.</item>
                           <item>N. VVotton.</item>
                        </list>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </body>
            <back>
               <div type="colophon">
                  <p>
                     <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> Imprinted at London in Powles Churcheyarde, by Iohn Cawood, Prynter to the Quenes Maieſtie.</p>
               </div>
               <div xml:lang="lat" type="license">
                  <p>Cum priuilegio Regiae Maieſtatis.</p>
               </div>
            </back>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>
